Guide to the William Shockley Papers SC0222
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
William Bradford Shockley papers
1860-2002
bulk
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Shockley, May Bradford
Shockley, William
SC0222
260.25 Linear Feet
Professional and personal papers relating to Professor Shockley's controversial interests in environment and genetic influences on intelligence; research on transistors and electronics; and science education. Also includes extensive family materials including diaries and correspondence.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Professor William B. Shockley, 1980 and 1986, and of Mrs. William B. Shockley, 1990, 1995, 2007 and 2008.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of engineering at Stanford (1958-1975; emeritus 1975- ). Shockley was co-recipient of the Nobel Prize in physics, 1956.
Related Collections
Stanford University Archives also holds William Spicer's William Shockley and eugenics collection, 1965-1970 (SC0864) and Isabel Steiner Karkau's William Shockley and eugenics collection, 1966-1973 (SC0595), as well as Shockley's father, William Hillman Shockley papers, circa 1860-circa 1920 (SC1108).. The Hoover Institution also holds the William Shockley miscellaneous papers, 1980 (80124).
Description of the Collection
Professional and personal papers relating to Professor Shockley's controversial interests in environment and genetic influences on intelligence; research on transistors and electronics; and science education. Also includes extensive family materials including diaries and correspondence.
Arrangement
The main accession is arranged in four series: 1. Telephone Conversations; 2. Correspondence; 3. Correspondence Enclosures; 4. May Bradford Shockley/Shockley Family Papers. Subsequent accessions to the collection follow.
Nobel Prize winners; Intelligence tests; Intelligence levels; Electrical engineering -- California.; Electronics; Genetics.; Electrical engineering -- Study and teaching.; Transistors; Science -- Study and teaching; Shockley, William; Stanford University. Department of Electrical Engineering. Faculty; Shockley, May Bradford; Shockley, William
- Telephone conversations [audio recordings], 1973-1978; Series 1
  - 1973 Mar 03 - Aug 29 (Box 1)
  - 1973 Aug 26 - 1974 Jan 15 (Box 2)
  - 1974 Jan 16 - Jun 17 (Box 3)
  - 1974 Jun 17 - 1975 Jan 08 (Box 4)
  - 1975 Jan 08 - 1975 May 29 (Box 5)
  - 1975 May 27 - Nov 30 (Box 6)
  - 1975 Nov 30 - 1976 May 16 (Box 7)
  - 1976 May 13 - 1977 Mar 07 (Box 8)
  - 1977 Mar 07 - 1978 Sep 08 (Box 9)
- Correspondence, 1958-1971; Series 2
  Scope and Contents
  Series II contains volumes of incoming and outgoing chronological correspondence files. A typed index, listing dates, names and institutional affiliation of all correspondence and correspondents is in the front of each volume. The files span the years 1958 - 1971. Subjects discussed in this correspondence include the importance of genetic factors in intelligence, the overpopulation problem and birth control, eugenics, student unrest (particularily,incidents at Stanford), environmental issues (specifically air pollution) and various requests for Dr. Shockley to speak, and for reprints of his articles. These files are stored in ten record storage boxes and two manuscript boxes.
  - Incoming, I-A, 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Incoming, I-B, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Outgoing, I-A, 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Outgoing, I -B, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Incoming, I-C, 1966-01 - 1966-10 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Incoming, 2-A, 1966-11 - 1966-12 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Outgoing, 1-C, 1966-01 - 1966-09 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Outgoing, 2-A, 1966-10 - 1966-12 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Incoming, 3-4, 1967-01 - 1967-09 (Box 2)
  - Outgoing, 3, 1967-01 - 1968-03 (Box 2)
  - Incoming, 5-A, 1967-10 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Incoming, 5-B, 1967-11 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Incoming, 6, 1967-12 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Incoming, 7, 1968-01 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Incoming, 8, 1968-02 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Incoming, 9, 1968-03 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Incoming, 1968-4 - 1968-10 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Outgoing, II-A, 1968-05-01 - 1968-05-14 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Outgoing, 4, 1968-04 - 1968-05 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Outgoing, 5, 1968-06 - 1968-09 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Incoming, 11-B, 1968-05-15 - 1968-05-31 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Incoming, 12, 1968-06 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Incoming, 13, 1968-07 - 1968-08 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Incoming, 14, 1968-09 - 1968-10 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Incoming, 15, 1968-11 - 1969-01 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Incoming, 16, 1969-02 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Incoming, 17, 1969-03 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Outgoing, 6, 1968-10 - 1969-02 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Outgoing, 7, 1969-03 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Incoming, 18 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Incoming, 19, 1969-05 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Outgoing, 8, 1969-04 - 1969-05 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Incoming, 20, 1969-06 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Incoming, 21, 1969-07 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Outgoing, 9, 1969-06 - 1969-07 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Incoming, 22, 1969-08 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Incoming, 23, 1969-09 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Incoming, 24, 1969-10 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Incoming, 25, 1969-11 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Outgoing, 10, 1969-08 - 1969-09 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Outgoing, 11, 1969-10 - 1969-11 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Incoming, 26, 1969-12 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Outgoing, 12, 1969-12 - 1970-01 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Incoming, 27, 1970-01 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Incoming, 28, 1970-02 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Outgoing, 14, 1970-02 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Incoming, 29, 1970-03 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Outgoing, 15, 1970-04 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Incoming, 30, 1970-05 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Outgoing, 16, 1970-04 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Incoming, 31, 1970-05 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Incoming, 32, 1970-06 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Incoming, 33 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Outgoing, 17-19, 1970-05 - 1970-07 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Incoming, 34, 1970-08 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Outgoing, 20-22, 1970-08 - 1970-10 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Incoming, 36, 1970-10 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Incoming, 37, 1970-11 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Incoming, 38, 1970-12 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Incoming, 39, 1971-01 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Outgoing, 23, 1970-11 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Outgoing, 24, 1970-12 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Outgoing, 25, 1971-01 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Incoming, 40, 1971-02 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Outgoing, 26, 1971-02 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Incoming, 41, 1971-03 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Outgoing, 27, 1971-03 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Incoming, 42, 1971-04 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Outgoing, 28, 1971-04 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Incoming, 43, 1971-05 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Outgoing, 29, 1971-05 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Incoming, 44, 1971-06 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Outgoing, 30, 1971-06 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Incoming, 45-1, 1971-07-01 - 1971-07-15 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Incoming, 45-2, 1971-07-15 - 1971-07-31 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Outgoing, 31-1, 1971-07-01 - 1971-07-16 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Outgoing, 31-2, 1971-07-16 - 1971-07-31 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Outgoing, 32, 1971-08 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Incoming, 46, 1971-08 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Incoming, 47-1, 1971-09-01 - 1971-09-16 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Incoming, 47-2, 1971-09-16 - 1971-09-30 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Outgoing, 33, 1971-09 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Incoming, 48, 1971-10 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Outgoing, 34, 1971-10 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Incoming, 49-1, 1971-11-01 - 1971-11-16 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Incoming, 49-2, 1971-11-16 - 1971-11-30 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Outgoing, 35, 1971-11 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Incoming, 50, 1971-12 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Outgoing, 36, 1971-12 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Correspondence enclosures, 1958-1971; Series 3
  Series 3 consists of enclosures, received with incoming letters, which are filed separately from this incoming correspondence. These files are chronological and date from May 1958 to December, 1971. They fill twelve record storage boxes.
  - 1958-05 - 1967-04 (Box 1)
  - 1967-05 - 1967-11 (Box 2)
  - 1967-12-05 - 1968-04-23 (Box 3)
  - 1968-04-24 - 1968-09-10 (Box 4)
  - 1968-09-11 - 1969-04-29 (Box 5)
  - 1969-05-01 - 1969-10-29 (Box 6)
  - 1969-11-03 - 1970-03-31 (Box 7)
  - 1970-04 - 1970-08-27 (Box 8)
  - 1970-09-01 - 1971-03-29 (Box 9)
  - 1971-04 - 1971-06-30 (Box 10)
  - 1971-07-01 - 1971-09-29 (Box 11)
  - 1971-10 - 1971-12 (Box 12)
- Shockley Family Papers, Series 4
  Scope and Contents note
  Series IV contains the personal papers of May Bradford Shockley, William B. Shockley's mother. Along with financial and legal records are correspondence with friends and family, dating back to May Shockley's youth in California and her life in a Nevada mining town around the turn of the century, and continuing until the early 1970's. Also included is correspondence and papers of other family members, including William Hillman Shockley (father of W.B.S.). Several journals of Sarah Hillman Shockley, 1859-1965, along with a draft of her autobiography and other writing efforts are in this series, as well as several diaries and address books belonging to May Bradford Shockley. In addition, there are two folders of genealogical information, one for W.H. Shockley, and the other for May B. Shockley's family. This series also contains many photographs, and several scrapbooks of the Shockley family, dating back to the 1860's.
  May Bradford Shockley's papers also include some information on her son. One folder contains old school diplomas, commencement brochures and newsclippings about William B. Shockley. There is also intermittent correpondence from him and his wife, to M. B. Shockley, 1924-1966.
  Shockley, William Hillman; Shockley, May Bradford
  - MBS Financial papers: letters about stock certificates, 1966; MBS income tax returns, 1961-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - MBS Biographical, genealogical information on the Shockleys; correspondence from MBS to relatives; MBS' will and notices of rent increases, 1906-1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Two manuscripts by Nanelia S. Doughty, niece of MBS: "Tonopah Nevada," 28 typed pages, 1975 "May Bradford of Tonopah" 94 typed pages, 1969 Letters: Seymour K. Bradford to wife (MBS' parents) and from May Bradford to mother, all written from and about Tonopah, Nevada, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bradford mining claims, Tonopah, Nevada, 1906 and letters about the employment of A.R. Fletcher as survey chairman, 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - MBS Collection of poetry written by MBS, "Efforts Poetic," n.s. MBS letters to friends and relatives, 1934. Also "Hidden Hemispheres" by A.R. Fletcher (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - MBS letters to mother, Sallie J.L. Bradford, 1883-1907 MBS resume, n.s. 4 typed pages Nancy N. Carter, school honor cards 1845-50 Sallie Ward, school honor code and compositions, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - WHS Correspondence between William H. Shockley, Ray Lyman Wilbur and Pedro De Lemos re. loan of Chinese porcelain to Stanford museum for long term exhibit, 6/27/1918 - 8/14/1925 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - MBS driving tests, 1958-1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - MBS incoming correspondence from friends and daughter-in-law, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - MBS incoming and outgoing correspondence about her job as a deputy mineral surveyor for Nevada, 1906-1908 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - MBS misc. bills, receipts, stock divendend notices, lists of figures, list of stock transactions, 1929-1954 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - MBS correspondence with James Purdy and Sons about disposition of gun owned by MBS and stored by company, 1941-1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - WBS materials kept by his mother (MBS); includes diplomas, MIT commencement program from 1936, news clippings, exercise brochure with WBS as model, brochure about Shockley transistor company, IR tests of WBS at age 8 and 9 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - MBS correspondence, 1931-1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - MBS misc. correspondence (family and friends), 1902-1941 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - MBS bound notebook filled with lecture notes from Geology I course taken from J.C. Branner at Stanford, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - MBS correspondence/legal documents about trust and sale of 527 Waverley, Palo Alto, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - WHS income tax, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - SJLB SJL Ward (later, SJL Bradford) MBS' mother, incoming correspondence (some letters are addressed to MBS whose name at the time was Cora May Wheeler), 1910 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - MBS letter printed in TIME magazine (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Chinese art (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Thorwald Siegfried suit threat, 1927; SKB and Paul E. Bowers, 1929; Walter Shockley re birth of WH Shockley, 1942, 1927-1942 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - MBS diaries, daily engagement books, 1898-1975, address books, 1925 & undated, appointment calendars, 1938-1940 (Box 2)
  - WHS general ledger, 1925 record book, 1911-1915 (Box 2)
  - MBS bank statements from checking account, 1929-1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - MBS misc. collection of phone bills, auto bills, insurance papers, PG&E bills, receipts (in cardboard expandable file), 1950-1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - MBS maps of Tonopah Mining District, Nevada, 1903-05 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - SJLB, SKB Photo of S.K. Bradford and S.J.L. Bradford with children (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - MBS Photo of M.L. Bradford and May Bradford Shockley, c. 1890 (also contains pencil sketches of Bradford family members, date and author unknown, but may have been MBS) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - MBS incoming correspondence, 1901-03 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Early photographs of William B. Shockley (Box 4)
  - MBS, WHS, Alden, Wheeler: letters, genealogy, photographs, scrapbooks, journals/diaries. (Box 4)
  - MBS Scrapbook; postcards of Europe and USA, collected by Cora May Bradford, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Photographic album of the Shockleys in the 1890s and perhaps earlier; only a few are identified and the owner's name is not known (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook of Nancy M. Carter Ward: postcards, greeting cards, poems, prayers, articles clipped from newspapers, memorablilia, 1880 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Memorabilia, loose items, from Nancy M. Carter Ward scrapbook, 1880 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook with clippings, articles, reprints about WHS Diablo Mine, mining in general, fishing, whaling, mining related industries, 1880-1900 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Diploma & Grades, MBS (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - MBS Incoming Correspondence; Includes letters from WBS, 1959-09 - 1962-03 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - MBS Incoming Correspondence, 1944, 1962-1964 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - MBS Incoming Correspondence; Important Letters, 1953-1962 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - MBS Incoming Correspondence, 1953-1962 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - MBS Incoming Correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - MBS Incoming Correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - MBS Incoming Correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - MBS Incoming Correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - WBS Incoming Correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - MBS Correspondence from Jean Bailey Shockley (first wife of WBS) to MBS, 1943-1966 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - MBS correspondence to S.K. Bradford, 1911-1935 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - WBS correspondence to MBS, 1944-58 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - WHS book plates (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - MBS and L.V. Siegfried, 11/2/1935 trust agreement; WHS trust agreement, 2/14/1925 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - MBS correspondence about trust agreements, 1939-1972 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Stock records, 1955-1967 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - MBS Legal papers, SJLB will, MBS house insurance for 261 Waverley, Palo Alto, deed to 261 Waverley, Bill of Sale, 261 Waverley (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - MBS correspondence about stocks, 1941-1964 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - MBS correspondence about Bank of America trust fund, 1965-1972 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - MBS statements about Bank of America trust fund, 1960-1967 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - MBS statements about Bank of America trust fund, 1968-1970 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - MBS statements about Bank of America trust fund, 1970-1973 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - MBS large brown folder tied with string containing financial advice, 1929-1930 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - ticker tape of 1929 stock market crash (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - MBS and WHS letters to SKB, 1909-1911. Collection of postcards, many blank, 1905-06. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - WHS, MBS correspondence, mostly to SKB, 1909-1913 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - MBS Letters to MBS upon death of WHS, and copies of death announcements, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - WBS Letters to MBS from JBS and WBS, 1925-1942 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - WBS Letters to MBS from JBS and WBS, 1933-1942 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - MBS Correspondence between MBS and SJLB, 1928-1938 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - WHS incoming correspondence, 1886-12 - 1888-04 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - WHS incoming correspondence, 1882-11 - 1884-10 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Minutes from church aid society meetings, in several different hands, Santa Fe, N.M., 1880-05-11 - 1882-06-20 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - MBS collection of plant speciments with botanical descriptions, 1896 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - WHS account book, Candelaria Nevada, 1889-1891 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 19th century Bible belonging to N.H. Wheeler (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 19th century scrapbook of color stickers pasted onto pages (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - WBS and JBS letters to MBS, also contains WBS school records, 1927-1940 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - MBS art show, Washington D.C. clippings, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - MBS art show, 1922 and art club, 1951: programs and correspondence (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - MBS and WHS important personal papers re: MBS adoption, SJLB divorce, marriage certificate, WHS death certificate, passports, DAR, early 1900's (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - MBS background material for Herbert Hoover Oral History Program in which she participated: correspondence with L.H. Hoover, Christmas cards from the Hoovers, 1920's; also an article from the NEVADAN on MBS life and career (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - MBS oral history about her relationship with the Hoover family, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - WHS diaries (Box 12)
  - SJLB IRS returns, plus her will and trust papers, 1918-1975 (Box 13A, Box 13B)
  - Photos of the Shockley family
    - [23v77] BROWN 9x12 ENVELOPE: "WHS BOX (New Bedford) IDENTIFIED PHOTOS" Four 6x9 white envelopes: William H. Shockley with brothers Geo. P and Walter A New Bedford Houses Sylvia Taber Shockley Pratt, WHS half sister plus children Marion Pratt (Barney) and Ned Pratt (f of Sylvia McMean) Bonham and misc. large prints of Walter A. Shockley and porch scene 2 children, 4 adults (Box 14)
    - [24Jun77] BROWN 10x13 ENVELOPE: "MISC WHS AND NEW BEDFORD" Brown 6x9 New Bedford Houses and Young Phoenix in ice Loose portrait WHS reading, one in white tie, Waldorf Astoria also George P. White 6x9 with negative for one WHS reading portrait (Box 14)
    - [1944] Alvin Freeman and Mrs. With WBS, MBS, Bill Hansen and Betsey, Danny and Ruth White. Some 45 Maple Ave. Madison N.J. with Alison and Billy. Portrait mounts of SJLB in wheel chair and some of Alison at about eight (Box 14)
    - A group of items, some with notes by MBS. From bottom up as follows: Candelaria Wm house Mt. Diable mine -- The Lilleles house. Shockley family homes -- and New Bedford architecture [also I added a sailboat] MBS pre-wedding + portrait with baby W=S+portrait for 1922 D.C. art show. All these duplicated in F(2) MBS Exhibit: Photos of paintings. Biographical note. Also photo of W.S. and Lee de Forest. (Box 14)
  - Southwest Museum, LA, Nov 21 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - WHS notes on pres, Chips, Bic on MBS, 1919-1922 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Food Admin, 1918-1919; 1977 Jun 22 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Bio from Julia Sanitarium; Misc. Itrs., Clips on Lou Henry Hoover; DL Webster Oliver Ros, 1925 Mar 17 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Price Lists, Bio Material, Speech; Misc Photos - H. Hoover, Bat Mwertly, 1977 Jun 22 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - LA Sunday Times, Work DC, Pagesy Payer; Shoup Letter, Blance Morse Kenna Doc 1920; Painting, Cilipsi Catalogue, 1921 Nov 27; 1920; 1921 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Mildred Broke Hoover; Correspondence Lou Henry Hoover; Mrs. Hoover Exhibit; Wash DC Art Clippings (Authors Clip Service), 1929; 1915-1923; 1922 Nov (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Ehreich Gal NY; Correspondence Gamps + Grand Canyon, 1924; 1923 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Crocker Gal, Sacramento, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Labaudt Art Gallery SF; Palo Alto Art Club, 1948; 1947-1952 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Charter Member; Chiefly PA Art Club, Rickey Studio Club (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - $125 Portrait Russell Harris, Sacramento; Re Sho; Preies, Labels, Pasadena, Sacramento; PA Art Club Photos + Negatives; Paintings, 1947; 1947-1952; 1921-1922 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - MBS in HS Grad dress SJLB in studio; Photos of MBS, SJLB, LVS, unknown (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Photos of MBS + Unknown (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Couch Repair MBS; Am Extra Catch all - House @ 23466 Corta Via built by Dirk and Clarence Harvey in 1961; MBS by Walter Gallatini; MBS copy CI Mary Lou, 1961; 1961; 1955; 1969 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Kingston, New Mexico, looking NW; SKB; MBS, SJLB, SKB, NC after Ward, John Nelson Ward; SJLB + SKB Long Beach, 1898; 1884; 1910 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - MBS pre weeding pic + clipping; WHS, WBS, Belgium; Wm. Badford Sherkley + family; See 5A here for 527 Waverly group, 1910 Aug; 1910-1954 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Stanford, CA - MBS; Bullfrog; Key Pittman Lightning; French Nole, 1908; 1906; 1904; 1906 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - "Photos important to me MBS"; X-mas, New Years party, pastel of MBS, MBS poems, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Carthage Mo, Palo Alto, Orego, NM, Stanford, 1898-1902 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Scrapbook (Box 15, Volume 21)
  - William Hillman Shockley-biographical, 1920s (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - William Hillman Shockley-outgoing letter, 1920s (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - 19th century maps and information on mines in China, pre-1900 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - William Hillman Shockley-autobiography mss, 1920 Sep 21 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - William Hillman Shockley-correspondence, notes, and pamphlets on religion, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - William Hillman Shockley-correspondence, notes, and pamphlets on the training of children, 1912-1914 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Short biographies of William Hillman Shockley, 1926, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - William Hillman Shockley-English correspondence course and mss, 1908-1909 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - SF Chronicle article about prosperity in the Sudan, 1919 Feb 14 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence about Shockley diaries and biographies, 1963-1965 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - William Hillman Shockley-Sudan trip, 1905 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Panama Pacific English Conference, 1915 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - William Hillman Shockley-mentions in news reports in Candelaria and Walker Lake, NV, 1880-1902 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - William Hillman Shockley-Mt. Diablo mill and mining company, 1892undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - William Hillman Shockley-letters to mother, 1880s (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - William Hillman Shockley-diaries, book project, undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - William Hillman Shockley-checkbook, 1913-1923 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - William Hillman Shockley-notes, 1889 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Spelling reform, undated (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - William Hillman Shockley-diary pages, undated (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Ledger, undated (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - William Hillman Shockley-letters received, botany, 1878-1890, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Notebook, undated (Box 16, Folder 23)
- Additional material, Accession ARCH-1986-050
  - Bell Lab Materials
    - Bell Lab News - Misc. Clippings (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bell Lab News - AT&T Patent / R&D (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bell Labs Record and other magazine articles (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - BTL Material (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1. SU. Biograph (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 2. BTL Biograph (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 3. BTL Films list (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 4. Try Simplest Cases + Memory Code (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 5. Unpublished Ms (Box 1, Folder 2)